<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on RECON mapping first aid</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on RECON mapping first aid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Population flows</title>
      <link>/2017/08/31/flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/31/flows/</guid>
      <description>This code shows how to map population flows between different locations. The code produces an interactive leaflet map with great circle arcs connecting origin and destination locations. It also shows how to save the leaflet map as a png file in case we want to get a static version of the map. This post was inspired by the example that Nathan Yau shows here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create custom maps from openstreetmap</title>
      <link>/2017/08/30/osmplotr-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/30/osmplotr-maps/</guid>
      <description>Openstreetmaps is a gigantic collection of geographical information. Most often, it is used to create base maps for plots. This small tutorial shows how you can generate your own custom openstreetmap base map for ggplot2 and how to extract data from OSM.
Our goal is to create a map of Freetown with just the roads. In addition we will search openstreetmap for hospitals in Freetown and display them on a map as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example to plot spatiotemporal areal data</title>
      <link>/2017/08/30/stplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/30/stplot/</guid>
      <description>Background Often surveillance data will be reported through a line list whereby cases have information on the time of symptoms and the administrative area of residence (e.g. district). As well as plotting a time series of cases, a map of aggregated case counts at the administrative area would be informative. [Data aggregated at the administrative level is known as areal data].
Here we show how to create such a map for multiple time periods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping point data</title>
      <link>/2017/08/30/map-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/30/map-points/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we illustrate how to generate maps using point data. Typically, individual points will correspond to the location of a reported case. We will illustrate several approaches including: basic point maps, representing point density, and using spatial clustering to approximate spatial structures.
The data: a simulated Ebola outbreak in Freetown This example uses the latest devel version of the http://www.repidemicsconsortium.org/outbreaks/ package, which can be installed by typing:
 devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;reconhub/outbreaks&amp;quot;)  Note that this requires devtools to be installed with its dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>